

631-294-1908

Long Island, New York

<u>constantinechutis@gmail.com</u> <u>Linkedin</u> - <u>Medium</u> - <u>Github</u> www.constantinechutis.com

About Me

Developer/designer with 8 years of experience creating and managing websites, multimedia, and virtual reality applications. Transitioned to Software Engineering to bolster my knowledge base and combine my design and development skills with JavaScript, React, and Ruby to create full stack applications and websites that are visually enticing and interactive.

Skills

General: Software Engineering, Front End Development, Backend Development, Virtual Reality Development, Web Development & Design,

Graphic Design, Asset Creation, Print Media, Logo Design, UI/UX Creation, Style Guide creation, Mockup Design, Search Engine

Optimization

Applications: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, VSCode, Visual Studio, Unity 3D, Xcode, Sketch, Invision, Janus VR, cPanel, Spark AR

Platforms & Frameworks: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, Redux, C#, Objective C, Electron, A-Frame, Node,

Git, Wordpress, PHP

Relevant Experience

Web Developer, Prestige Worldwide Industries, LLC. Patchogue, NY.

Dec 2013 - May 2019

- Managed and created all media and marketing for 8 subsidiaries and their projects
- Created and maintained 15 websites using Wordpress and HTML5/CSS
- Developed an interactive Virtual Reality game that educates users on the crime scene cleanup industry and its related hazards using Unity/C#
- Led an initiative to create a Virtual Reality enabled website using Janus VR, allowing people to enter virtual company space
- Developed and maintained company app in Xcode/Objective C, published in iOS App Store
- Trained and managed two web designers and an SEO specialist

Developer/Designer, Leviathan Design Group LLC. - Self-Employed.

2010 - Present

- · Develop websites and media for companies, such as law firms, personal trainers, realtors, and a Chamber of Commerce
- Create visual themes, styles, websites, advertisements and logos for clients' companies
- Develop and maintain website for New York Rangers Podcast, Blueshirts Breakaway

Web Developer, Zultech Systems. Deer Park, NY.

Nov 2009 - Dec 2013

- Created websites, videos, logos and print media for clientele
- Designed presentations via After Effects for the computer shop's floor, which highlighted sales and general information

Certifications & Organizations

AIGA/NY Membership – 2017 CompTIA A+ Certification – 2009

Education

Flatiron School. New York, NY - Software Engineering & Fullstack Development 2019
Hunter Business School. Medford, NY - Computer Repair & Networking 2009
Suffolk Community College. Selden, NY - General Studies & Graphic Design courses 2002-2004

Projects

Headspace VR - Github | Demo

Web-browser based React/A-Frame Virtual Reality App that allows users to relax in various environments and a personal theater to watch movies

- Developed Ruby on Rails API backend with endpoints for environments, movie selections, thumbnails and media data.
- Utilized A-Frame for WebVR 3D rendering of environment photospheres and personal theater rendering, UI, particles, cameras, lighting, canvas and objects.
- Utilized Preact with Redux for lightweight state changes that operated independently of A-Frame's rendering thread for speed.
- Implemented 3D models in obj and gITF format for web optimal use.

Recursive - Github | Demo

Trello-clone React web app that allows users to create projects and tasks within those projects to track and assign deadlines

- Developed Ruby on Rails API backend for full CRUD actions on user's account information and project/task details.
- Utilized React CSSTransitions for animated component loading/unloading.
- Developed fully controlled search/filter options for user experience.

Orbs//OS - Github | Demo

Electron / Web Vanilla JS mock operating system app that contains personalized desktop and 8 micro-apps

- Developed Ruby on Rails API backend with endpoints for user account data (Stored locally on disk due to app operating in Electron Shell).
- Implemented drag and drop windows for micro-apps.
- Developed and designed micro-apps such as text editor, code editor, task manager, timer, calculator, digital piano and web browser using Vanilla JS.
- Utilized customizable user preferences such as custom wallpapers and icons.
- Utilized WeatherAPI to show user's current temperature and conditions based on location on the operating system's desktop.

Cryptochambr - Github

Ruby on Rails app for mock trading of Cryptocurrencies. Data pulled from CoinMarketCap API dynamically displays real time currency information and trade history.

- Developed Ruby on Rails front end/backend that allows full CRUD actions on user info, cryptocurrency stats, and current funds.
- Utilized CoinMarketCap API for up-to-date currency values, information and SVG icons.
- Implemented mock trading logic that allows users to add funds, purchase and sell coins, as well as provide transaction history which shows profit/loss on investments.